<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

    <!--EN: kiiro-->
    <KiiroXenotype.label>kiiro</KiiroXenotype.label>

    <!--EN: A humanoid species with cat-like ears and cat-tailed limbs, the kiiro race. 

As natives who have lived on this planet for thousands of years, the technology of the kiiros has developed slowly after reaching the medieval level: they always have more things to do than to develop science and technology, such as napping, gossiping, sunbathing and enjoying leisure time. Even when they moved out of their free time to work, they were more than happy to do something related to art. Because of their gentle and non-combative character, their society has always maintained a high degree of harmony and stability throughout their long history, with very few conflicts and disputes, and this has resulted in the fact that although they have the gift dexterous in fighting, they are not good at it. 

But all this began to change when the rough outsiders landed on this planet and got a firm foothold: lack of combat experience and training, technology has not been developed to a great extent, the kiiros appear very powerless in the face of foreign enemy attacks, many villages and towns were attacked and fallen, the survival of the kiiros once fell into a crisis, which forced the kiiros to give up their peaceful life, and set out on a difficult and long road of living. 

However, the invasion of foreign enemies not only spread the war, but also brought the opportunity of technological development to kiiros. With the exposure to the technology brought by the outsiders, the technological level of the kiiros has exploded in a short period of time through introduction and imitation, and the seeds of the industrial age have quietly sprouted within this ancient and backward race......-->
    <KiiroXenotype.description>Une espèce humanoïde avec les oreilles et la queue d'un chat, l'espèce kiiro.
    
    Comme espèce indigène de la planète depuis des millénaires, la technologie des kiiros se développa lentement après avoir atteint le niveau médiéval. Elles avaient toujours d'autres choses à faire que de développer la science et la technologie, telles que faire la sieste, faire des commérages, prendre un bain de soleil et profiter du temps libre. Même lorsqu'elles travaillaient, elles se contentaient de faire quelque chose lié à l'art. À cause de leur nature gentille et paisible, leur société restait toujours très harmonieuse et stable tout au long de leur histoire longue, avec très peu de conflits et disputes. Le résultat : bien qu'elles soient douées en combat agile, elles n'en sont pas compétentes.
    
    Tout cela changea quand les étrangers arrivèrent sur cette planète et s'établit. Les kiiros manquaient d'expérience en combat, entraînement militaire et leur technologie était inférieure à celle des nouveaux arrivants. Les kiiros semblaient impuissantes face aux attaques des ennemis étrangers, beaucoup de villages et villes furent attaqués et tombèrent. La survie des kiiros était en danger, et cela forçait les kiiros d'abandonner leur vie paisible et commencer une route difficile et longue pour survivre.
    
    Cependant, l'invasion des ennemis étrangers propagea la technologie et la possibilité de la développer, ainsi que la guerre. Après l'exposition à la technologie des étrangers, le niveau technologique des kiiros s'augmenta extrêmement vite par l'introduction et l'imitation, et les germes de l'ère industrielle poussèrent silencieusement à l'intérieur de cette espèce ancienne et arriérée.</KiiroXenotype.description>


</LanguageData>